

## MOHAMMAD AHSANUL ISLAM

#### **Software Engineer**

Mobile: 01791001120

Email: mdahsanul.sowmik@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-ahsanul-islam-b79100187/

Github: https://github.com/ahsanulSowmik

Experienced software engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success. Well-versed in technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Highly adaptable and 2.5+ years of experience in software development. I want to be in such a company where, I will have the opportunity of enhancing my knowledge and I am able to provide a competitive advantage with my knowledge and skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Trainee Software Engineer (Java 2EE) **At BJIT.** 

April 2023 – July 2023 Baridhara, Dhaka

 As a Trainee Software Engineer at BJIT, I was actively engaged in learning and developing my skills in Java Spring Boot, reactive programming, and microservices while contributing to real-world projects.

\_\_\_\_\_\_

# Software Developer At Limerick Resource Ltd.

Oct 2022 – March 2023 Mohammadpur, Dhaka

• I have been immersed in the exciting world of Flutter mobile application development. Here, my role involves creating innovative solutions and contributing to the development of cutting-edge mobile applications.

## Junior Developer At Deshi IT

Jun 2021 - Sep 2022

Panthapath, Dhaka

• I actively contributed to diverse projects involving Android and Laravel development. As part of the team, I gained valuable experience in creating and implementing solutions for both mobile and web platforms, honing my skills as a versatile software developer.

\_\_\_\_\_

#### Instructor / Technical Consultant

#### At Bangladesh Innovation Academy

Jun 2020 - present

Dhanmondi, Dhaka

• Instructor/Technical Consultant at Bangladesh Innovation Academy since June 2020, teaching programming (C++, Scratch, Basic Python) to school-level students, fostering the next generation of coding enthusiasts.

### **Projects**

• Training Management System - As the sole developer, I proudly spearheaded the end-to-end development of a comprehensive Transportation Management System (TMS) using Java Spring Boot and React.js. This self-driven project empowers businesses with an efficient and seamless logistics solution, showcasing my expertise in full-stack development and dedication to innovation.

AppLink: <a href="https://github.com/ahsanul-J2EE/tms">https://github.com/ahsanul-J2EE/tms</a>

• **SO Track** - This is a tracking app, where all salesperson activity will tracking as per route plan. Senior managers can get reports and findings for a salesperson.

AppLink: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.limerickbd.limtech\_erp

• **BEXCA** - This is a community mobile app and web application, where all Barisal cadet's student are connected with each other's.

AppLink: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.bexca.bexca\_mobile\_app

- **Objective Test** This is an objective test is an android app where students can practice for their exam questions anywhere. AppLink: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.deshiit.bcs">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.deshiit.bcs</a>
- Live Train Tracking This is an android app.
- Doctor Portfolio A doctor's personal portfolio with an admin panel developed with Laravel.
  Live link: <a href="https://drhskallol.com/">https://drhskallol.com/</a>

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS**

- Mar 2019 participation Certification at Intra department programming contest (32nd position)
- July 2019 participation Certification at Take off programming contest(34<sup>th</sup> position)
- July 2019 participation Certification at Intra department programming contest (12<sup>th</sup> position).
- Participation Certificate at National Programming Contest 2019 preliminary.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming Technologies: C, C++, Python.
- Mobile app Technologies: Java, Flutter.
- Web Programming Technologies: Spring Boot, Jwt, Hibernate, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ReactJS, PHP, Laravel,
- Version Control: Git, GitHub.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor in Science (B.Sc.) in Software Engineering,

**Daffodil International University** 

Jan 2019-Dec 2022 • CGPA: 3.64/4.00

\_\_\_\_\_\_

2017 Higher Secondary Certificate(HSC) in Science,

BIAM Model School And College, Bogura, Rajshahi

• GPA:5.00/5.00

\_\_\_\_\_

2015 Secondary School Certificate (SSC) in Science,

Vasha Shaheed Abdul Jabber Ansar VDP School And College, Gazipur, Dhaka

• GPA:5.00/5.00

#### **REFERENCES**

Asif Khan Shakir | Senior Data Analyst at Save the Children International.

Gmail: asif.khan.shakir@gmail.com

Mobile: 01917607480

Shuvo Joseph | CEO at DeshilT.

Gmail:shuvojoseph@gmail.com

Mobile: 01717473714